python 3.11 came out and just by
upgrading to it your code can become
between 10 and 60 percent faster
and today we're going to take a look at
five new python 3.11 features that I am
very excited about let's first talk
about speed python 3.11 is up to 10 to
60 percent faster than Python 3.10 and
that is thanks to the faster C python
project python the programming language
is just an idea a specification of how
the syntax look like and what the rules
are C python is a c program that
implements python it takes python code
reads it and sends the instructions to
the CPU faster C python is a project
where the creator of python GitHub and
rosum along with other developers at
Microsoft are trying to make python 5
times faster in the next three to four
years they plan a performance increase
of one point five times per year which
is what we can already see with version
3.11 if you use things like numpy or
tensorflow which is code that is already
written in C you won't see any major
speed Improvement but for tools programs
and web servers that are using pure
python code this speed up is a game
changer python 3.11 also has better
error messages they are now more clear
informative and helpful this code right
here will cause an error this is how the
error looks like in Python 3.10 and this
is how it looks like in python 3.11
python 3.11 can now not only tell you
the line of code that caused the error
but also it can show you where in the
line the error came from in talking
about errors python 3.11 also comes with
something called exception notes now you
can add more messages to your exceptions
allowing you to provide more context in
into what went wrong on this code we are
catching the exception and adding a note
that will later show up on the console
under our error I think this feature
will be used mostly by libraries and
testing Frameworks to tell us what went
wrong in a better way I don't really see
myself using this directly on the topic
of exceptions python 3.11 also has
exception groups when something goes
wrong and there is more than one error
we can now use exception group to stack
multiple exceptions together getting an
output like this one on the console
you can even create nested exception
groups and the console will also display
them in a cool nested way if you want to
handle the errors of an exception group
all you have to do is use the new try
except star syntax here you can see how
we have an exception group that raises
two type error in two value error and
you can also see how using the accept
star syntax we are able to catch them
all last but not least python 3.11 also
comes with a new module called Tamil lip
Tomo which stands for Tom's obvious
minimal language is a file format for
configuration files that is used almost
everywhere and that I'm sure you've seen
before tunnel Leaf is a new module of
the Python standard library for Reading
Terminal files so if you have a
config.tomel file like this one you can
just read it using Tomo lib like this
and if we print that data to the console
we will get some something like this
thank you for watching this video I hope
you found it helpful let me know in the
comments what is your favorite python
3.11 feature and if you would like me to
make more videos about python write it
down below and I'll make it happen if
you want to become a python developer
for absolutely free click the link below
because there you will find a free 7
hour python course that I made
especially for you for absolutely free
see you on the next video stay healthy
stay awesome be happy
see you on the next one bye